<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EucaStack – Understanding VPC Networking Concepts</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/</link><description>Recent content in Understanding VPC Networking Concepts on EucaStack</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Domain Name System (DNS)</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_dns/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Domain Name System (DNS) is an Internet standard that maps unique DNS names (for example: &lt;a href="https://www.example.com">www.example.com&lt;/a>) to the underlying public IP address (for example: 128.0.0.1).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eucalyptus provides a DNS service with your cloud. By default, EC2 classic (EDGE mode) and VPCMIDO mode default subnet instances that are launched in your Eucalyptus cloud are automatically assigned public and private DNS names from the Eucalyptus DNS service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Elastic Network Interfaces (ENIs)</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_elastic_net_interfaces_eni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_elastic_net_interfaces_eni/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In Eucalyptus VPC, networking to instances (VMs) is delivered in the form of Elastic Network Interfaces (ENIs). ENIs are virtual network interfaces that can be attached to and/or detached from instances in a VPC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attributes of an ENI (private address, public address, Elastic IP, MAC address, security groups, and source/destination check flag) follow the ENI as it is detached from an instance and attached to another instance. An instance in a VPC has a default ENI attached, which is called the primary ENI. The Primary ENI cannot be detached.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additional ENIs (up to a total of eight) can be attached to instances as needed. ENIs in different subnets can be attached to the same instance, but all ENIs and the instance must reside in the same Availability Zone. Users may need to manually bring up and configure secondary ENIs from within instances.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Route Tables</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_route_tables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_route_tables/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A route table defines how traffic is directed in your network. Each subnet in your network has to be associated with one (and only one) route table, but a route table can have multiple subnets associated with it. A default route table (which simply contains a local route that allows communication within the VPC) is automatically created for you when you create your VPC. New subnets will get this route table by default, but you can replace it with a custom route table that enables you to explicitly control subnet traffic.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
For more information on route tables, see the on Wikipedia.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Docs: Internet Gateways</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_internet_gateways/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_internet_gateways/</guid><description>
&lt;p>An Internet gateway is an object that runs inside of your VPC and provides communication between VPC instances and the Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To use an Internet gateway in your VPC, you attach the gateway to your VPC, make sure your route tables direct Internet traffic to the Internet gateway, and configure your security groups to allow traffic through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By default, instances loaded into any non-default VPC have private IP addresses (so they can communicate with other instances in the same VPC), but they do not have public IP addresses. For an instance to be able to communicate with the Internet gateway, it must have an associated public IP address. The default VPC comes with a pre-configured Internet gateway, and all instances that are launched into the default subnet receive a public IP address, so these instances have Internet access.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Network Address Translation (NAT) Gateways</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_nat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/user_guide/vpc_intro/vpc_networking_concepts_intro/vpc_concepts_nat/</guid><description>
&lt;p>NAT Gateways enable instances in private VPC subnets to initiate communication with the Internet (and receive responses), but prevents connections to be initiated from the Internet. Traffic bound to the Internet from instances in private subnets should be directed to a NAT gateway (through the use of route tables), which will translate the source address to its own Elastic IP and route it to the Internet. The destination will send a response back to the Elastic IP (i.e., the NAT gateway), where the address translation will be reversed and delivered to the originating private IP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NAT Gateways should be created in public VPC subnets, and have an Elastic IP associated. Private VPC subnets should have its route table manually updated to direct Internet-bound traffic to a NAT gateway.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>