<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EucaStack – Configure Eucalyptus</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/</link><description>Recent content in Configure Eucalyptus on EucaStack</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Configure SELinux</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/configure_selinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/configure_selinux/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We recommend enabling SELinux on host systems running Eucalyptus 4.4 services to improve their security on RHEL 7. Enabling SELinux, as described in this topic, can help contain break-ins. For more information, see &lt;a href="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux/7/html/SELinux_Users_and_Administrators_Guide/chap-Security-Enhanced_Linux-Troubleshooting.html">RedHat SELinux&lt;/a> documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to set boolean values on Storage Controller (SC) and Management Console host machines. If your network mode is VPCMIDO, you also set a boolean value on the Cloud Controller (CLC) host machines. &lt;strong>To configure SELinux on Eucalyptus 4.4 :&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On each Storage Controller (SC) host machine, run the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>setsebool -P eucalyptus_storage_controller 1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This allows Eucalyptus to manage EBS volumes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On each Management Console host machine, run the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>setsebool -P httpd_can_network_connect 1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This allows the Management Console&amp;rsquo;s HTTP proxy to access the back end.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-success" role="alert">
&lt;h4 class="alert-heading">Note&lt;/h4>
If you can&amp;rsquo;t access the console after starting it, this KB article might help: .
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>If your cloud uses VPCMIDO networking mode, on the Cloud Controller (CLC), run the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>setsebool -P httpd_can_network_connect 1
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This allows the CLC&amp;rsquo;s HTTP proxy to access the back end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SELinux is now configured and ready to use with your Eucalyptus 4.4 cloud.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Configure Network Modes</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/configure_network_modes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/configure_network_modes/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This section provides configuration instructions for Eucalyptus networking modes. Eucalyptus overlays a virtual network on top of your existing network. In order to do this, Eucalyptus supports these networking modes: EDGE (AWS EC2 Classic compatible) and VPCMIDO (AWS VPC compatible).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Create Scheduling Policy</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/sched_pol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/install_guide/eucalyptus/configuring_euca/sched_pol/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This topic describes how to set up the Cluster Controller (CC) to choose which Node Controller (NC) to run each new instance.In the CC, open the &lt;em>/etc/eucalyptus/eucalyptus.conf&lt;/em> file. In the &lt;code>SCHEDPOLICY=&lt;/code> parameter, set the value to one of the following: &lt;code>GREEDY&lt;/code> When the CC receives a new instance run request, it runs the instance on the first NC in an ordered list of NCs that has capacity to run the instance. At partial capacity with some amount of churn, this policy generally results in a steady state over time where some nodes are running many instances, and some nodes are running few or no instances. &lt;code>ROUNDROBIN&lt;/code> (Default) When the CC receives a new instance run request, it runs the instance on the next NC in an ordered list of NCs that has capacity. The next NC is determined by the last NC to have received an instance. At partial capacity with some amount of churn, this policy generally results in a steady state over time where instances are more evenly distributed across the set of NCs. Save the file.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>