<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EucaStack – Identity and Access Management (IAM) Guide</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/</link><description>Recent content in Identity and Access Management (IAM) Guide on EucaStack</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: IAM Overview</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/overview/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Welcome to the IAM Guide. IAM is an acronymn for Identity Access Management. IAM is used for account management where a cloud administrator establishs accounts, users and their identities. You can do many things with IAM, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Create and manage IAM users and groups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set quotas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Establish access policies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create and manage roles&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This document is intended to be a reference. You do not need to read it in order, unless you are following the directions for a particular task.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Work with IAM</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/iam_intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/iam_intro/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The Eucalyptus IAM design provides more layers in the hierarchical organization of user identities, and more refined control over resource access. This complies with the Amazon AWS IAM service. There are a few Eucalyptus-specific extensions to meet the needs of enterprise customers. The IAM service is a global service, meaning a user can interact with any region using the same credentials, subjected to the same policies, and having uniformly accessible and structured principals (accounts, users, groups, roles, etc.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Manage Identities Overview</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_identities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_identities/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Like IAM, the user identities in Eucalyptus are organized into Accounts. An account is the unit of resource usage accounting, and also a separate name space for many resources, for example, security groups, key pairs, users, and so on. Unique ID (UUID) or a unique name identifies an account. The account name is equivalent to IAM’s account alias. In Eucalyptus, the account name is used to manipulate accounts in most cases. However, to be compatible with AWS, the EC2 commands often use account ID to display resource ownership. There are command line tools to discover the correspondence of account ID with the account name. For example, lists all the accounts with both their IDs and names.
&lt;img src="https://www.eucastack.io/images/iam_diagram.png" alt="image">
An account can have multiple users, but a user can only be in one account. Within an account, users can be associated with Groups. A Group is used to attach access permissions to multiple users. A user can be associated with multiple groups. Because an account is a separate name space, user names and group names have to be unique only within an account. Therefore, user X in account A and user X in account B are two different identities. Both users and groups are identified by their names, which are unique within an account (they also have UUIDs, but rarely used).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Authentication and Access Control Best Practices</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/security_bp_access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/security_bp_access/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This topic describes best practices for Identity and Access Management and the account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="identity-and-access-management">Identity and Access Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Eucalyptus manages access control through an authentication, authorization, and accounting system. This system manages user identities, enforces access controls over resources, and provides reporting on resource usage as a basis for auditing and managing cloud activities. The user identity organizational model and the scheme of authorizations used to access resources are based on and compatible with the AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) system, with some Eucalyptus extensions provided that support ease-of-use in a private cloud environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a general introduction to IAM in Eucalyptus, see &lt;a href="https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_auth/understanding_identities/concepts_eiam/">Access Concepts&lt;/a> in the IAM Guide. For information about using IAM quotas to enforce limits on resource usage by users and accounts in Eucalyptus, see the &lt;a href="https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_auth/understanding_identities/access_policies/access_policy_quota/">Quotas&lt;/a> section in the IAM Guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/IAMBestPractices.html">Amazon Web Services IAM Best Practices&lt;/a> are also generally applicable to Eucalyptus.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="credential-management">Credential Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Protection and careful management of user credentials (passwords, access keys, X.509 certificates, and key pairs) is critical to cloud security. When dealing with credentials, we recommend:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Limit the number of active credentials and do not create more credentials than needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only create users and credentials for the interfaces that you will actually use. For example, if a user is only going to use the Management Console, do not create credentials access keys for that user.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use and or to get a specific set of credentials if needed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Regularly check for active credentials using commands and remove unused credentials. Ideally, only one pair of active credentials should be available at any time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rotate credentials regularly and delete old credentials as soon as possible. Credentials can be created and deleted using commands, such as and .&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When rotating credentials, there is an option to deactivate, instead of removing, existing access/secret keys and X.509 certificates. Requests made using deactivated credentials will not be accepted, but the credentials remain in the Eucalyptus database and can be restored if needed. You can deactivate credentials using and .&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="privileged-roles">Privileged Roles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>eucalyptus&lt;/code> account is a super-privileged account in Eucalyptus. It has access to all cloud resources, cloud setup, and management. The users within this account do not obey IAM policies and compromised credentials can result in a complete cloud compromisation that is not easy to contain. We recommend limiting the use of this account and associated users&amp;rsquo; credentials as much as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For all unprivileged operations, use regular accounts. If you require super-privileged access (for example, management of resources across accounts and cloud setup administration), we recommend that you use one of the predefined privileged roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Account, Infrastructure, and Resource Administrator &lt;a href="https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_auth/understanding_identities/concepts_eiam/access_roles/">roles&lt;/a> provide a more secure way to gain super privileges in the cloud. Credentials returned by an assume-role operation are short-lived (unlike regular user credentials). Privileges available to each role are limited in scope and can be revoked easily by modifying the trust or access policy for the role.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Manage Users and Groups</title><link>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_auth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.eucastack.io/docs/iam_guide/managing_auth/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id="manage-users-and-groups">Manage Users and Groups&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Eucalyptus IAM supports user, group, and role based access controls and STS (Security Token Service) for temporary credentials.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>